Finding Aid for Michigan Political History Society oral history collection, 1995-2013
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Political History Society oral history collection 1995-2013
Michigan Political History Society.
9796 Aa 2
28 optical disks in 2 boxes DVDs
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was received in multiple accessions from the Michigan Political History Society (donor no. 8575 ) in 2009-10.
Periodic additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Michigan Political History Society was founded in 1993 as a non-partisan organization to promote knowledge of the political history of the state of Michigan. The Society has a newsletter and sponsors meetings, some of these honor political figures of the past, others are lectures by authors who have written about state politics. Since 1995, the Society has sponsored a program of oral history interviews. The oral history program, titled the James J. Blanchard Living Library of Michigan Political History, is an on-going project of the Society.
The collection consists of 28 DVDs of oral history interviews with state political figures, most of them active in the period of 1950 to 2000. The interviews are conducted by individuals knowledgeable about state political history. The content of the interviews are both about the individual's career and about the issues and personalities of the time. These interviews are with political and labor leaders, past members of the state legislature, a Detroit mayor, and a member of the state constitutional convention of 1961-1962.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Allen, Glenn S., 1914-2001.; Crim, Bobby.; Bluestone, Irving.; Coomes, Francis J.; Danhof, Robert.; Dingell, John D.; Democratic Party (Mich.); Downs, Tom, 1916-; Fletcher, Peter.; Fraser, Douglas A. (Douglas Andrew), 1916-2008.; Grand Hotel (Mackinac Island, Mich.); Gribbs, Roman S., 1925-; Griffin, Robert P. (Robert Paul), 1923-2015; Hart, Adelaide, 1900-; Jeffrey, Mildred, 1911-2004.; Kelley, Frank J. (Frank Joseph), 1924-; Lindemer, Lawrence B.; Maynard, Olivia.; McLaughlin, William F., 1932-; Musser, Dan.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-; Owen, Gary M.; Peterson, Elly Maude, 1914-2008; Republican Party (Mich.); Traxler, Robert.; VanderLaan, Robert.; Waldron, Robert E.
Contributors:
Cawthorne, Dennis.
Genre Terms:
DVDs.; Oral histories.
- Oral History Interviews, 28 optical disks DVDs
  (arranged by date)
  - Douglas Fraser, Former President, UAW, Interviewed by Tom Downs April 8, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Irv Bluestone, Retired Vice President, UAW, Interviewed by Tom Downs April 22, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Elly Peterson, Michigan Republican Chair 1965-1969 Interviewed by Bill Ballenger, May 1, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Adelaide Hart, Former Democratic Vice-Chair, Interviewed by Tom Downs June 26, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Tom Downs -- Vice Chair 1961 Constitutional Convention, Interviewed by Bob LaBrant, August 21, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Mildred Jeffrey -- Community Activist, Interviewed by Tom Downs December 28, 1995 (Box 1)
  - U.S. Senator Robert P. Griffin, Interviewed by Dennis Cawthorne July 25, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Retired Court of Appeals Judge, Glenn S. Allen, Interviewed by Tom Downs November 22, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Robert E. Waldron, Former Speaker of the House, Interviewed by John Kerekes August 11, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Judge Robert Danhof, Interviewed by Bob LaBrant September 20, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Frank J. Kelley, Former Attorney General, Interviewed by Leon S. Cohan December 10, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Olivia Maynard, Former Democratic Vice-Chair, Interviewed by Lynn Jondahl May 31, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Bob Traxler, Former US Congressman, Interviewed by Bill Ballenger May 14, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Bobby Crim, Former House Speaker, Interviewed by, Lynn Jondahl July 10, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Larry Lindemer, Former GOP Chair, Interviewed by Bill Ballenger July 16, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Roman Gribbs, Former Detroit Mayor, Interviewed by Bill Ballenger July 22, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Jerry Coomes, Former Catholic Conference Director, Interviewed by Bill Ballenger August 20, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Peter Fletcher, Former GOP Committeeman, Interviewed by Bill Ballenger October 15, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Gary Owen, Former Speaker of the House, Interviewed by Lynn Jondahl October 17, 2008 (Box 1)
  - William McLaughlin, former chairman of the State Republican Party, Interviewed by Bill Ballenger March 17, 2009 (Box 1)
  - John D. Dingell, Congressman, Interviewed by Lynn Jondahl May 29, 2009 (Box 2)
  - Robert VanderLaan, Former State Senate Majority Leader, Interviewed by Bill Ballenger July 13, 2009 (Box 2)
  - R.D. Musser, Chairman Grand Hotel, Mackinac Island, Michigan, Interviewed by Bill Ballenger December 17, 2009 (Box 2)
  - U.S. Senator Carl Levin, Interviewed by Lynn Jondahl October 19, 2010 (Box 2)
  - L. Brooks Patterson, Oakland County Executive, Interviewed by Bill Ballenger November 10, 2011 (Box 2)
  - Dennis W. Archer, Former Michigan Supreme Court Justice and Mayor of Detroit, Interviewed by Lyn Jondahl December 21, 2012 (Box 2)
  - Paul Hillegonds, Former Speaker of the House, Interviewed by Bill Ballenger January 10, 2013 (Box 2)
  - Conrad L. Mallett, Jr., Former Chief Justice of the Michigan Supreme Court, Interviewed by Bill Ballenger January 10, 2013 (Box 2)